A Guide to the Correspondence, Reports, Petitions and Resolutions Relating to the Construction, Staffing and Governance of the University of Virginia, 1821 (1825-1826)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Correspondence, Reports, Petitions and Resolutions Relating to the Construction, Staffing and Governance of the University of Virginia 1821 (1825-1826)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-1/3/3.801
This collection consists of 14 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection is an archival transfer (provenance unknown), found in UVA Chronological file on 1980 July 17.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence, reports, petitions, and resolutions relating to the construction, staffing, and governance of the University, particularly during the student unrest of October 1826, bearing endorsements by Thomas Jefferson
Correspondents include A. S. Brockenbrough, John Patton Emmet, Thomas H. Key, George Long, and George W. Spotswood. Authors of reports include Charles Bonnycastle, Robley Dunglison and George Tucker.
Contents List
- Owen Reynolds to L[ouis] H. Giradin re: application for professorship of mathematics, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson 1821 Aug 10, ALS, 3 p.
- Philip Sturtevant to A[rthur]; S[picer] Brockenbrough re: timber for composite capitals, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson 1825 Jun 6, ALS, 2 p.
- Petition of students to Visitors of the University of Virginia, requesting division of term and longer vacation, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson 1825 Sep, 3:00 PM
- DS, Faculty resolution on disgraceful conduct of student by George Tucker, chairman of the faculty of the University of Virginia, 2 p., and ADS by Robley Dunglison, secretary, 1 p., both endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1825 Oct 2
- Resolution of students of the University of Virginia not to divulge names of rioters, copy, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson 1825 Oct 3?, 3:00 PM
- Faculty to [Visitors of the University of Virginia] re: reprimands and expulsions of student rioters, 1 p. List of rioters, three expulsion orders signed by Robley Dunglison and George Tucker, 3p., copies, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1825 Oct 6
- T[homas] H. Key and George Long to Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia, letter of resignation, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1825 Oct 6, ALS, 1 p.
- T[homas] H. Key and George Long to Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia, requesting clarification of terms of resignations, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1825 Oct 6, ALS, 1 p.
- Student petition to the European faculty of the University of Virginia, denying intent to offend, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1825 Oct, ADS, 3 p.
- Philip Sturtevant to Arthur S[picer] Brockenbrough re: price of composite capitals, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1826 Jan 1, ALS, 2 p.
- Arthur S[picer] Brockenbrough to Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia re: composite capitals offered by Philip Sturtevant, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1826 Apr 2, ALS, 1 p.
- Geo[rge] W. Spotswood to Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia re: unsafe habitation, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. 1826 Apr 3, ALS, 2 p.
- ALS, John P[atton] Emmet to Rector and Visitors of the University of Virginia, submitting two reports by faculty committees, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson, 1 p., report on need for police, by Bonnycastle, Tucker, and Emmet, 4 p., and report on enactments concerning student disorders by Key, Long, and Blaettermann, 4 p. 1826 Apr 3
- G[eorge] Long to Visitors of the University of Virginia re: requirements for diploma in Greek, endorsed by Thomas Jefferson. [ante 1826 Jul 4], ALS, 1 p.